Guide to the George J. Hecht papers, [ca. 1915]-1974.
Hecht, George J. papers, [ca. 1915]-1974.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
George J. Hecht papers, [ca. 1915]-1974.
3473
George J., Hecht 1895-1980.
2.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, news clippings, and articles.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, news clippings, and articles relating to George J. Hecht (Cornell University Class of 1917). Correspondents of note include John Lovejoy Elliot of the Ethical Culture Society and the Hudson Guild, William DeForest, James G. Blain, and Senators Hubert Humphrey, Lister Hill, Cleveland Bailey, and Robert Kennedy. Also included are three taped interviews and transcripts, 1974.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Publisher.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, news clippings, and articles relating to George J. Hecht (Cornell University Class of 1917). Correspondents of note include John Lovejoy Elliot of the Ethical Culture Society and the Hudson Guild, William DeForest, James G. Blain, and Senators Hubert Humphrey, Lister Hill, Cleveland Bailey, and Robert Kennedy. Also included are three taped interviews and transcripts, 1974.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hecht, George J., 1895-1980.; Bailey, Cleveland.; Blain, James G.; DeForest, William.; Elliot, John Lovejoy.; Hill, Lister, 1894-; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978.; Kennedy, Robert F., 1925-1968.; Bailey, Cleveland; Blain, James G.; DeForest, William; Elliot, John Lovejoy; Hill, Lister, 1894-; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978; Kennedy, Robert F., 1925-1968; Ethical Culture Society.; Hudson Guild.
Subjects:
Education.; Public welfare.; Social service.; Publishers.; Education; Public welfare; Social service
INFORMATION FOR USERS
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Subdivisions: 1. Personal correspondence and family life; 2. Social welfare work; 3. Education and educational legislation; 4. Hecht publications.Arranged chronologically within subdivisions.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Subdivisions: 1. Personal correspondence and family life; 2. Social welfare work; 3. Education and educational legislation; 4. Hecht publications.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Personal Correspondence and Family Life
Series II. Social Welfare work
Series III. Education and Educational Legislation
Series IV. Hecht Publications
Series V. Miscellaneous Hecht Publications
CONTAINER LIST
- Personal Correspondence and Family Life, 1903-1967
  - Biographical Material, 1927, 1936, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Contains clippings, articles, and a photograph
  - Family Tree, 1953, 1955-1956, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Contains correspondence, tables, and photographs
  - Childhood and Youth, 1906, 1909, 1912-1913, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Contains correspondence
    Frankfort, Maurice
    Sister Beatrice
    Ethical Culture School
  - Cornell, 1913-1917 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Contains a Basserman draft
  - Letters from Cornell to parents, 1914, 1916, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters from Cornell to parents, 1917, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1922, 1925-1927, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Marriage, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Contains correspondence, clippings, photographs, and a Basserman draft
  - Meyer Hecht and Gella Stern Hecht (parents), 1886, 1891, 1903, 1917, 1919, 1922-1923, 1925-1926, 1930, 1937-1942, 1944, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Contains correspondence, photographs, and clippings
    Hecht, Meyer
    Stern Hecht, Gella
    Elliott, John Lovejoy
    Society for Ethical Culture
  - Maurice Frankfort, 1903, 1935, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Contains correspondence and a photograph
  - Beatrice Hecht letters (adolescent), 1917, 1920, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Freyda Hecht (wife), 1938, 1943, 1955, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Contains correspondence, clippings, and a photograph
  - Hecht children (Susan and George) childhood letters, 1931, 1937, 1941-1943, 1957, 1960-1961, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Contains correspondence, clippings, and photographs
  - Hecht Family Miscellany, 1903, 1930, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Contains photographs, correspondence, and memorabilia
  - Travel, 1936, 1939, 1950, 1952-1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Social Welfare Work, 1919-1974
  - Better Times - Early Days, 1920-1929, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Better Times, 1919, 1920-1924 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    United Neighborhood Houses
  - Better Times, 1925-1931 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Lehman, Herbert
  - Better Times, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Better Times Bulletins, 1920, 1922, 1924, 1926, 1930, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Welfare Council, 1923-1928 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Contains 1927-06-06 and 1927-11-21 copies of Better Times Bulletins
  - Welfare Council, 1923-1930, 1934, 1937-1938, 1940-1941, 1945, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Lane, Robert
    DeForest, William
  - Greater New York Fund, 1938-1941, 1940-02-23, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Blain, James G.
  - How The Greater New York Fund Happened to Get Started, 1926-1938, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Fakoner, Douglas P.
    Welfare Council, Executive Committee
  - Ethical Culture Society, 1919, 1927, 1939, 1942, 1959-1960, 1963, 1966, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    American Ethical Union
    Ethical Culture Schools
  - Hudson Guild, 1919, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - National Council of Social Work, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - UNICEF, 1953-1954, 1958, 1961, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Labouisse, Henry
    Pantaleoni, Helsenka
    United States Committee for UNICEF
  - United Jewish Appeal, 1930, 1944, 1963, 1965-1966, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Ben-Gurion, David
    Joint Distribution Committee
    Federation for the Support of Jewish Philanthropic Societies of New York City
  - Population Explosion and Birth Control, 1950, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    San Francisco Medical Center
    Population Reference Bureau
- Education and Educational Legislation, 1920-1974
  - Education and Educational Legislation, 1953, 1956-1958, 1963, 1965, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Kennedy, Robert
    Humphrey, Hubert
  - American Parents Committee, 1921, 1949, 1954-1959 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    U.S. Department of Labor, Children's Bureau
  - American Parents Committee, 1960, 1962, 1964-1965, 1967, 1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Hill, Lister
  - Handbook on Federal Grants-in-Aid, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    American Parents Committee
  - "In the Supreme Court of the United States, October Term 1966. Motion for Leave to File A Brief As Amicus Curiae and Brief of The American Parents Committee As Amicus Curiae" (Gault Case), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Bipartisan Citizen's Committee for Federal Aid for Public Elementary and Secondary Schools, 1959-1963, 1966, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Bailey, Cleveland
    Harlow, Bryce
  - Emergency Committee For The National Defense Education Bill; Citizens Committee for Extension of the National Defense Education Act, 1958-1959, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Elliott, Carl
    Johnson, Eric
    Benton, William
  - "The International Brains Race", 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Simplified Spelling and An International Language, 1959-1963, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
    International Language Review
- Hecht Publications, 1917-1973
  - Washington Service, World War I, 1917-1918, 1921, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    American Ambulance Field Service
    Bureau of Cartoons
    Bureau of Research
  - Correspondence from Washington, D. C. to parents, 1917, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
    National Committee of Patriotic Societies
  - Correspondence from Washington, D. C. to parents, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    U.S. Department of State, War Trade Boards
    Committee on Public Information
  - Cartoons (World War I), 1918 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Bulletin for Cartoonists, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Creel, George
  - Bulletin for Cartoonists, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - World War I, 1918, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    The Stars and Stripes
  - Boy and Girls Newspapers, 1934-1935, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    The Children's Newspaper of London, England
  - Comics (True Comics and WWII Comics), 1941, 1943-1948, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - World War II, 1938, 1940-1943, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Metropolitan Mothers Guide, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - School Supply and Equipment Directory, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Hecht's other magazines, 1938, 1940-1942, 1953, 1966-1967, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Better Babies
    Calling All Girls
    Children's Digest
    Humpty-Dumpty's
    Predictions of Things to Come
    True Comics
  - Parents' Magazine Enterprises, Inc., 1964-1966, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Parents' Magazine, 1926-1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Parents' Magazine, 1927-1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Possible inspiration for Parents' Magazine, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Rockefeller, John D.
  - Parents' Magazine, 1920's, 1924-1929 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Gavit, John Palmer
    Hill, Patty S.
    Meloney, William Brown
    Russell Sage Foundation
  - Children, The Magazine For Parents, 1926-01 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Dean Russell's Inquiry Regarding Children, The Magazine For Parents, And the Replies He Received", 1927-03 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Russell, James
  - Editor's Handbook, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Parents' Magazine, 1920's, 1926-1929 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "The Greatest Profession in the World", 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Parents' Magazine, 1920's, 1926-1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "A Suggested Plan For A Management Corporation To Conduct The Publishing Operations of 'Boy's Life,' 'The American Girl,' And 'The Parents' Magazine.", 1930-05-23 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Parents' Magazine, 1930's, 1930-1934 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Hoover, Herbert
    Roosevelt, Eleanor
    Motion Picture Theatre Owners of America
    New York Urban League, Inc.
  - Parents' Magazine, 1930's, 1935-1937 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    DeForest, Johnson
    Hill, George Parmley
    Hill, Patty Smith
    Lenroot, Katharine
    Littledale, Clara Savage
    Roosevelt, Franklin
    Ruml, Beardsley
    Greater N.Y. Fund
  - Parents' Magazine, 1930's, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Hoover, J. E.
    Perkins, Frances
    Better Parenthood Week
    National Father's Day Committee
  - Parents' Magazine, 1930's, 1930-1931, 1934, 1936-1938 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Parents' Magazine, 1940's, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Parents' Magazine, 1940's, 1940-1945, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Parents' Magazine, 1940's, 1940-1945 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Parents' Magazine, 1950's, 1950-1953, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Truman, Harry
  - Parents' Magazine, 1950's, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Parents' Magazine, 1960's, 1960-1961, 1963-1967, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Kennedy, John F.
    Lindsay, John
    Ribicoff, Abraham
    Calling All Parents
  - International Federation of The Periodical Press, 1959-1960, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Parents' Magazine, 1960's, 1963, 1965, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Parents' Magazine, Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Parents' Magazine, Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Baker and Taylor Co., 1960, 1966-1967, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence Courses, 1961, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    Parents' Magazine Foundation for Child Welfare, Inc.
    University of Wisconsin Home Study Department
  - F.A.O. Schwartz (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous, 1924-1973 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Titles for Basserman manuscript, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Basserman manuscript notes, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - "An Unpublished Biography: The First 70 Years (1895-1965) of the Life of George J. Hecht", 1966 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    Hill Basserman, Maude
- Miscellaneous Hecht Publications, 1966, undated
  - "Baby Care", Fall 1973, Spring 1974 (Box 3)
  - "Baby Care Digest", 1944 (Box 3)
  - "Books For Young Readers", Fall 1973, Fall 1974 (Box 3)
    Contains catalogues
  - "The Book Buyer's Guide", 1960-09 (Box 3)
    Baker and Taylor Co.
  - "Calling All Girls", 1965-12 (Box 3)
  - "Children's Digest", 1966-09, 1974-04, 1974-07 (Box 3)
  - "Expecting", 1974 (Box 3)
  - F.A.O. Schwartz catalogues, Christmas 1965, Christmas, 1966 (Box 3)
  - "Humpty-Dumpty's", 1973-01-1974-09 (Box 3)
  - "Parents' Magazine", 1944-1966-12 (Box 3)
  - "The Pictorial News Digest", 1943-06-06 (Box 3)
  - "Predictions", 1943, Winter 1946 (Box 3)
  - "School Management", 1932-03 (Box 3)
  - "Student's Guide To American Industry", 1959-1960 (Box 3)
    Pamphlet
  - "Young Miss", 1974-05 (Box 3)
  - Interviews with George J. Hecht, 1974-07-03-1974-11-25; TR-519-521
    3 tape recorded interviews and transcripts
    Hecht, George J.
    Densmore, Christopher